A Guide to Paul Bowles, Letters to Brion Gysin, 1975-1978
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Paul Bowles, Letters to Brion Gysin 1975-1978
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10501-h
This collection contains 13 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from Paul C. Richard of Templemore, Massachusetts on July 14, 1988.
Scope and Content Information
In this collection of letters to Brion Gysin, the American author and composer Paul Bowles discusses mutual acquaintances, Moroccan music, the Spanish Sahara war, the high cost of living in Tangier, and disruptions caused by Islamic holidays. He occasionally mentions his work or Gysin's.
Contents List
- Writes of spending two weeks with John Hopkins at Marrakech, the arrival of Gordon Sager from Tokyo, the rising costs of living in Tangier, Morocco, the music of Jilala, and the disagreement between Spain and Morocco over the Spanish Sahara. May 11, 1975, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Discusses the controversy surrounding the review of the [Master Musicians of] Joujouka record in Rolling Stone and Hamri's complaints about lack of payment for his participation in its production. July 28, 1975, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Mentions receiving a book from Gysin, his own translations of the work of Isabelle Eberhardt published by City Lights, and the visits of a few friends. September 27, 1975, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Mentions the Islamic holiday, Aachor, wartime conditions and their interference with the funtioning of the markets in Morocco, and news about friends. January 9, 1976, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Describes the circumstances behind the gift of stale kif delivered to Gysin in Paris by Lily Kalman and mentions rising prices in Tangier. March 25, 1976, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Thanks Gysin for Oeuvre Croisee; mentions Dan Bente and his regard for Let the Mice In, a visit by Christopher Isherwood, Alec Waugh's 78th birthday, Mrabet and his "constant scandals," and a cargo ship which wrecked in November of 1975 at Cape Spartel. July 5, 1976, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Speaks of an exhibit by Christopher Wanklyn at the Casino, Dan Bente's desire to go to Paris to write a biography about Gysin and possible stumbling blocks to his ambition, and Sidi Kacem with its sheep sacrifices. August 7, 1976, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Mentions hearing Gysin's voice on a Mauritanian tape, the intention of Targuisti to visit Gysin in Paris, Dan Bente's involvement in the Tangier Players, a Ghanaian drummer who has played with the Stones and Mongo Santamaria, and a sacrifice of a chicken by Mrabet. September 30, 1976, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Asks several questions about Gilles Dehon; mentions letters from Ira Cohen and Charles Henri Ford, the latter expressing "Neo-Istiamer thought;" asks "what is the matter with Susan Sontag? Mind or body?"; and furnishes a description of the archaeological site, Msoura. November 18, 1976, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Describes the foibles and strange behavior of their acquaintance, Gilles Dehon. January 26, 1977, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Writes that the expected cassette has still not arrived, that [William] Burroughs apparently likes Boulder, Colorado even in winter, and that Mrabet has been ill in a Spanish hospital. March 17, 1978, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Describes his tribulations resulting from a dog bite; expresses concern over the lack of progress in recovery of Mrabet; and discusses finances. April 14, 1978, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope
- Mentions the mystery of Gilles Dehon, a visit by Tennessee [Williams], and an incident during Ramadan when he was pelted with pebbles for "clandestinely nibbling a galleta on the beach at Merkala." November 7, 1978, TLS, 1 p., w/ envelope